<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Eve News</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://blog.python-eve.org/feeds/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Auto generate API docs</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/eve-docs</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Eve provides powerful capabilities for quickly building RESTful APIs. The
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/charlesflynn/eve-docs"&gt;Eve-docs&lt;/a&gt; blueprint extends these capabilities with API documentation. You
activate the blueprint in your launch script, and Eve-docs creates the
documentation from your existing Eve configuration file, with no additional
configuration required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="An example of eve-docs auto generated API documentation" src="static/images/evedocs-example.png" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eve-docs generates documentation in HTML using &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.github.io/bootstrap/"&gt;Twitter Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;. You can
expand each domain to show available endpoints and methods, and further expand
each method to show parameter details. Eve-docs also publishes the
documentation data as JSON for programmatic consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detail see the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/charlesflynn/eve-docs"&gt;project repo&lt;/a&gt; on Github.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Charles Flynn</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.python-eve.org,2013-06-17:eve-docs</guid><category>documentation</category><category>tools</category></item><item><title>Account Management and REST</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/account-management-and-rest</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately I have been receiving a lot of enquiries on how to properly handle REST
API authentication, so I wrote a couple of tutorials that will hopefully shread
some light on the topic. They're filed under &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python-eve.org/tutorials/account_management.html"&gt;RESTful Account Management&lt;/a&gt; and
cover both Basic and Token-Based Authentication scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the obvious immediate usefulness in solving the issue at hand, I find
that tutorials offer a golden opportunity to grasp how apparently unrelated
features can be assembled togheter to solve a problem. So just let me know if
you'd like to see more &lt;em&gt;howtos&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.python-eve.org,2013-05-30:account-management-and-rest</guid><category>tutorials</category></item><item><title>Official IRC Channel</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/official-irc-channel</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The official IRC channel for the project is now &lt;a class="reference external" href="irc://irc.freenode.net/python-eve"&gt;#python-eve&lt;/a&gt;. We left the
previous channel as it was accidentally named like a tool for the EVE ONLINE
space game, causing some players of that game to join in only to get totally
lost by our geek chatter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.python-eve.org,2013-05-20:official-irc-channel</guid><category>irc</category></item><item><title>Eve 0.0.6 Released</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/eve-006-released</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The two main features introduced by this release are &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python-eve.org/features.html#event-hooks"&gt;Event Hooks&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://python-eve.org/features.html#projections"&gt;Projections&lt;/a&gt;. Event hooks allow to subscribe to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;GET&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;POST&lt;/tt&gt;, &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;PATCH&lt;/tt&gt;,
&lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;DELETE&lt;/tt&gt; requests with mutiple callbacks. Projections are conditional queries
where the client dictates which fields should be returned by the API (when
projections are omitted the whole document is returned).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also added support for HEAD requests, made sure that only fields defined in
resource schemas are returned, and applied a bunch of performance
optimizations, especially with regard to &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;POST&lt;/tt&gt; (Eve now performs bulk
database inserts) and &lt;tt class="docutils literal"&gt;ETag&lt;/tt&gt; computation.  Also, if you have been
experiencing 400s make sure to download this release, as a couple of
significant bugs have been squashed. See the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/nicolaiarocci/eve/blob/develop/CHANGES"&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; for all the news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to all the people who contributed either with patches or by opening
tickets and reporting bugs. In no particular order: Ondrej Slinták, Thomas
Sileo, Tomasz Jezierski, Nicolas Bazire, Nicola Carlier, maksim2042, Xu Wang,
Asdine El Hrychy, hluz, chronidev, Gianfranco Palumbo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://crate.io/packages/Eve/"&gt;Eve 0.0.6&lt;/a&gt; while it's hot!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.python-eve.org,2013-05-13:eve-006-released</guid><category>releases</category></item><item><title>SQLAlchemy and Eve</title><link>http://blog.python-eve.org/sqlalchemy-and-eve</link><description>&lt;p&gt;There is an ongoing effort to develop a SQLAlchemy data layer for Eve. This is
interesting because it will allow the use of a wide range of SQL databases
(PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, etc.) as storage backends for Eve-powered REST
APIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current early prototype resides in its own &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/nicolaiarocci/eve/tree/sqlalchemy"&gt;sqlalchemy branch&lt;/a&gt;. We are in
the early stages of development and contributors are invited to join the ranks.
There is a lot of room for improvement at all levels: features, tests,
documentation, you name it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to lend a hand please come visit us on &lt;a class="reference external" href="irc://irc.freenode.net/evehq"&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt; so we can better
coordinate efforts. &lt;strong&gt;Jezier&lt;/strong&gt; has been working on the SQL features while
&lt;strong&gt;beatpanic&lt;/strong&gt; has been playing around with the test suite. Get in touch with
them or with me (I’m &lt;strong&gt;iaro&lt;/strong&gt; on IRC). If IRC is not your cup of tea feel free to
open a &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/nicolaiarocci/eve/issues"&gt;ticket&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:eve&amp;#64;nicolaiarocci.com"&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; or submit a pull requests: just make sure it is
against the sqlalchemy branch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Nicola Iarocci</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 15:39:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:blog.python-eve.org,2013-05-10:sqlalchemy-and-eve</guid><category>sqlalchemy</category></item></channel></rss>